Shaker Catalogs Collection
Shaker Catalogs Collection
1953-1997
1980-1995
0.5 linear ft.
Auction and dealer catalogs for items produced by or pertaining to the Shaker religious community.
4597675
Biographical History
The Shakers, formally known as the United Society of Believers in Christ's Second Appearing, are a religious sect founded in England in the 18th century. Groups of Shakers first came to America in the 19th century, settling in Mount Lebanon and Watervliet, New York. Shakers practice celibacy, pacifism, a communal lifestyle, and equality of the sexes, which has been a tenet of their society since the 1780s. They are also known for their simple living, architecture, and furniture. Today there is only one active Shaker community, Sabbathday Lake Shaker Village in Maine.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Shaker Catalogs Collection contains auction and dealer catalogs for books, pamphlets, antiques, furniture, and other items produced by or pertaining to the Shaker religious community. Included in the collection are a few catalogs from the United Society of Shakers themselves.
Arrangement of the Collection
Alphabetical by name or topic, then chronological.
Related Material
has a substantial amount of print and manuscript material related to the Shakers and to other communal societies and Utopian communities. Please refer to to locate additional manuscript material and to to locate print material.
Subject and Genre Headings
Publishing, printing and book arts; Religion and philosophy; De Wolfe, Scott.; Newell, David D.; Sherman, Milton, d. 1990.; Shakers.; Auctions -- United States.; Book auctions -- United States.; Booksellers and bookselling -- United States.; Auction catalogs.; Book catalogs.; Clippings (information artifacts)
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Unknown.
Inventory
- Auction catalogs
  - Miscellaneous, 1961-1974 (Box 1)
- Dealer catalogs
  - Harold Nestler, 1974; 1976 (Box 1)
  - David Newell, 1980-1984; 1990,; 1997,; undated; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Miton Sherman, 1986-1990; undated; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Scott De Wolfe, 1992-1994 (Box 1)
  - United Society of Shakers, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
- Printed material
  - Miscellaneous, 1953; 1972,; undated; includes supplemental bulletin of the National Association of Watch and Clock Collectors, Inc. (Box 1)